zumiez.com 2010-01-11

# Zumiez 411 Privacy & Security

Privacy and Security Policy

Updated 10/30/09

PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS SITE. FOR CHILDREN VISITING THIS WEB PAGE, ASK YOUR PARENTS TO GO OVER THIS WITH YOU.

By using http://www.zumiez.com ("Site") you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this policy, please do not use this Site. Your continued use of our Site following the posting of changes tot hese terms will mean you accept those changes. Zumiez reserves the right, as its sole discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy at any time.

Zumiez Inc. values the relationship we have built with our customers. Our customers' rights to privacy online and the concerns of parents for their children visiting our site are very important. In efforts to bring you a great shopping experience and keep you updated with current promotions, events and product, we may collect some personal information.

Why do we collect personal information? How do we use it? And when do we share it with other companies? All these questions will be answered in this privacy policy. Also, you will learn about your rights and choices in regards to the use of your information. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, contact Zumiez Customer Service:

  * Email us at: [help@zumiez.com](mailto:help@zumiez.com)
  * Call us Toll Free at: (877)828-6929
  * Write to us at:  
Zumiez Inc.  
6300 Merrill Creek Pkwy Suite B,  
Everett, WA. 98203  
Attn: Customer Service

From time to time our privacy policy may change; our most recent information will be posted on our Site. Look for the revision date; it will inform you on the latest day of modification.

Privacy of Children on Our Site

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA") requires that we inform parents and legal guardians about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information from children under 13 years of age; and that we obtain the consent of parents and guardians in order for children under 13 years of age to use certail features of our Site. Below we explain how we comply with COPPA. When we use the term "parent" below, we mean to include legal guardians.

Information should not be submitted to or posted at Zumiez.com by guests under 13 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian. If Zumiez.com learns that a guest under 13 years of age has submitted personally indentifiable information online Zumiez will take reasonable measures to delete such information from its databases and to not use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required by law).

Children can browse Zumiez.com without any personal information being collected. We do not collect personal information from children unless they register with our Site. Children may register in order to participate in sweepstakes or contests or to participate in an activity. We will not condition a child's participation in an activity on the child's disclosure of more personal information than is reasonably necessary to participate in the activity. The only information we collect from children during our registration process is:

  * Full name
  * Email address
  * Phone number

We collect birth dates to validate the ages of our guests, including children. We do not collect any other peronally indentifiable information from children during our registration process. We also will collect a child's e-mail address from a parent for the purpose of sending the child e-mail related to a subcription.

If a child registers for a sweepstakes or contest, we use the parent's e-mail address to notify the parent of the child's registration request and to get the parent's permission to allow the child's registration and entry. We may collect a child's e-mail address from the parent in order to send the child a newsletter. In addition, we may share a child's personal information with third parties to the extent reasonably necessary to protect the security of integrity of our Site; to take precautions against liability; to respond to judicial process; or to the extent permitted under provisions of law, to provide information to law enforcement agencies or for an investigation related to public safety. Information is shared with third party service providers to manage our customer information, including shipping, name and address verification, email distribution, market research and promotions management. Those parties have agreed to maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of the information. Parents have the right to consent to Zumiez's collection of their children's information without agreeing to allow Zumiez to disclose the information to third parties.

Parents always have the right to review personal information that we have collected from their children. At any time parents can refuse to permit us to collect further personal information from their child and can request that any personal information we have collected be deleted from our records. Parents may review, change or delete the personally identifiable information that we have collected from their children by logging on to the child's account at the [My Account Home Page](https://www.zumiez.com/modcustomer/account/login) located at https://www.zumiez.com/modcustomer/account/login. The parent will need to have their child's member name and password. There are instructions on the My Account home page explaining how to recover a password if the child has forgotten it. Parents can also contact our customer service department to review, change or delete the personal information that we have collected from his or her child by sending an e-mail to [help@zumiez.com](mailto:help@zumiez.com)

We will provide parents notice via email of any material changes in the way we intend to collect, use, and/or share children's personal information. Parents should consistently update their personal information to provide us current e-mail addresses. We will apply material changes in our Privacy Policy only in conformance with applicable law, including any applicable provisions of COPPA that require parental consent.

If you need further assistance, please send an e-mail with your questions or comments to [help@zumiez.com](mailto:help@zumiez.com)

  or write us at:

Zumiez, Inc.  
6300 Merrill Creek Parkway  
Suite B  
Everett, WA 98203  

You may also telephone us at (877) 828-6929. If you are not 18 years of age or older, you must have your parent or guardian's permission to call this number. 

NOTICE: Please visit http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/privacyinitiatives/childrens.html for information from the Federal Trade Commission about protecting children's privacy online. 

Information we Collect

We may collect information including: your name, postal address, billing address, telephone number, email address and, when necessary, credit card information when you:

  * Place an order online
  * Make a purchase at one of our Zumiez Retail Stores 
  * Return an item or make an exchange 
  * Inquire about our services 
  * Receive a gift package 
  * Create an account at Zumiez.com 
  * Register at an event
  * Subscribe to ZMail 
  * Subscribe to receive Text Messages 
  * Send a wish list
  * Shop with a Friend
  * Share your Shopping Bag
  * Rate, Review or Tag a Product or Service
  * Enter a contest or sweepstakes 
  * Are referred to us through a marketing promotion 
  * Participate in a marketing survey, promotion, or events

To protect our customers, all records and data you have provided, is kept in a secure database. _See Security section for more information._

We collect data every time someone accesses Zumiez.com. This information is gathered to improve your shopping experience. The types of data we are tracking are day and time the Site is accessed, the internet domain used to access the Site, the website visited prior to visiting our Site, the pages visited while on our Site. 

Using Information We Collect

Providing your information will simply help us offer products and services that we think you'd like to hear about. This information allows us to:

  * Offer information on past purchases
  * Improve our product selection
  * Process and track your order
  * Provide the services you request
  * Contact you about the status of an order
  * Send promotional and contest emails
  * Send you promotional material
  * Send you Zumiez Email
  * Send you a Text message
  * Identify your product and service preferences
  * Customize our communications to you
  * Provide information concerning products you have purchased
  * Improve our customer service

How We Use Email

We may communicate with our customers via email, phone or text only if the customer agrees to receive the communication. These emails may include:

  * Order confirmation
  * Shipment confirmation
  * Providing customer service 
  * Keeping you updated with new product, promotions and services

Zumiez.com will never ask you through email to provide personal information including credit card numbers, passwords, or bank account numbers.

Information We Share With Others and Your Privacy Rights

When you shop or visit one of our stores or one of our websites we may share information about you to improve your shopping experience. We contract with service providers to maintain and manage our customer information, including credit card processing, shipping, name and address verification, email distribution, market research and promotions management. We provide these companies with only the information they need to perform their services and work closely with them to ensure that your privacy is respected and protected. These companies are prohibited by contract from using this information for their own marketing purposes or from sharing this information with anyone other than Zumiez. We generally do not authorize any of these service providers to make any other use of your information. In addition, when we partner with another company to offer or provide products, services, contests or promotions, we may compare our customer list with theirs to identify our common customers. Zumiez and its marketing partners may use that information to fulfill our respective obligations to you and for future promotional activities.

When we offer contests and promotions, with or without a marketing partner, you may be required to provide certain personal information in order to participate. In these cases, we will give you the choice not to receive promotional email messages or other communications from us regarding our products, services, contests, and promotions. In this case, however, Zumiez, or one of its affiliates may still need to contact you, for example, to notify winners and to fulfill promotional obligations. In the unlikely event of a sale of some or all of our business, Zumiez will disclose your personal information to a purchaser that agrees to abide by the terms and conditions of this privacy policy.

Zumiez reserves the right to disclose information about you as required by law, in response to legal process and law enforcement requests, and as necessary to protect the property, interests and rights of Zumiez, its affiliates, and others.

Updating or Reviewing Your Information

Did your personal information change? No problem, you can update, review or delete your personal information related to your account with Zumiez.com. This may include change of name, addresses or contact information. You have two ways to update this information:

Online: First go to Zumiez.com and log into your account using your username and password. Once you have logged in to your account, you can edit your profile by selecting <Account Dashboard> located in "My Account"

Phone: Zumiez.com Customer Care Toll Free at (877) 828-6929

Your Choice About Receiving Promotional Communications

We want to keep you updated, that is, if you want to hear about it. Zumiez will only correspond with customers who have agreed to receive communication. If you would like to stay updated with Zumiez events, promotions, new product and much more; Sign up for Zmail! 

If you no longer want to receive this information, contact us by:

  * Phone: Toll Free at (877) 828 6929
  * Email: [help@zumiez.com](mailto:help@zumiez.com)
  * Postal Address:  
Zumiez Inc.  
6300 Merrill Creek Pkwy Suite B  
Everett, WA. 98203

Cookies and Pixels Tags

A "cookie" is the term we use to describe a small data file that many Web sites use to write a file onto your hard disk. A cookie can contain data like an ID number used to track what pages were visited. Cookies do not have the ability, by itself, to be used by a Web site to obtain person information about the user or to read information from your computer. Cookies are simply there to help improve your experience with Zumiez.com. Why we use cookies:

  * View items placed in shopping cart
  * Track products that have been visited
  * Track when Zumiez.com has been visited
  * Track pages that have been visited
  * Determine whether a visitor came to Zumiez.com from a particular internet link or banner advertisement

The use of cookies is an industry standard, you'll find them at most major Web sites. We never save passwords or credit card information in cookies. If you prefer not to receive cookies from Zumiez.com, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence, or you can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser.

Security

We respect your personal privacy so we take all appropriate steps to keep your personal information confidential. Currently we use the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol to safeguard your information, which is an encryption method. You can tell you are using the SSL encryption when a gold or blue padlock appears in the corner of your Microsoft browser.

Links to Other Sites

For your convenience Zumiez.com may contain links to other web sites. Linked web sites operate independently, we are not responsible for webcasting or any other form of transmission received from any linked site. We advise reading the linked site's policies to ensure a better shopping experience.

Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of the Zumiez who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [insert email] or write to us:

Zumiez.com Privacy Rights  
6300 Merrill Creek Pkwy Suite B  
Everett, WA. 98203  
(877) 828-6929  

Questions or Comments

Have questions or comments about this policy? Let us know by contacting us at:

Zumiez.com Customer Care  
6300 Merrill Creek Pkwy Suite B  
Everett, WA. 98203  
(877) 828-6929
